<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Carlos Rellan personal website</title>
    <link>https://carlosrellan.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://carlosrellan.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Carlos Rellan personal website</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://carlosrellan.github.io/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Carlos Rellan personal website</title>
      <link>https://carlosrellan.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mining tools from the prehistoric quarries in Serra Llarga (NE Iberia): Preliminary results from lithological and techno-morphological approaches</title>
      <link>https://carlosrellan.github.io/publication/journal-article/2025_terradas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carlosrellan.github.io/publication/journal-article/2025_terradas/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connections with other populations in the Iberian Peninsula</title>
      <link>https://carlosrellan.github.io/publication/chapters/2025_oxbow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carlosrellan.github.io/publication/chapters/2025_oxbow/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aplicaciones Gis en Arqueología</title>
      <link>https://carlosrellan.github.io/teaching/gis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carlosrellan.github.io/teaching/gis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Seminaario del Máster Universitario de Arqueología de la Universidad de Granada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://masteres.ugr.es/arqueologia/docencia/plan-estudios/guia-docente/M71/56/1/49&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt; a la página de la asignatura en la web de la UGR.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zotero.org/groups/5732947/gis_en_arqueologa_mster_arqueologa_ugr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt; al grupo de Zotero con la bibliografía de la asignatura.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nueva página web</title>
      <link>https://carlosrellan.github.io/post/data-visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carlosrellan.github.io/post/data-visualization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bienvenid@ a la versión renovada de la página web personal de Carlos Rellán&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuevas Tecnologías para la Difusión y Puesta en Valor del Patrimonio Arqueológico</title>
      <link>https://carlosrellan.github.io/teaching/nntt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carlosrellan.github.io/teaching/nntt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Asignatura de cuarto curso del Grado en Arqueología de la Universidad de Granada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://grados.ugr.es/ramas/artes-humanidades/grado-arqueologia/nuevas-tecnologias-la-difusion-y-puesta-valor-del-patrimonio-arqueologico&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt; a la página de la asignatura en la web de la UGR.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zotero.org/groups/6013819/nuevas_tecnologas_para_la_difusin_y_puesta_en_valor_del_patrimonio_arqueolgico_grado_ugr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt; al grupo de Zotero con la bibliografía de la asignatura.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Las industrias pulidas en sillimanita durante la Prehistoria Reciente de Europa Occidental</title>
      <link>https://carlosrellan.github.io/event/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carlosrellan.github.io/event/example/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A multi-analytical study of the Montelirio beaded attires: Marine resources, sumptuary crafts, and female power in copper age Iberia</title>
      <link>https://carlosrellan.github.io/publication/journal-article/2025_garcia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carlosrellan.github.io/publication/journal-article/2025_garcia/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recensión de / Review of: Estelle Gauthier, Murielle Georges-Leroy, Nicolas Poirier y Olivier Weller (Dirs.). ARCHAEDYN: dynamique spatiale des territoires de la Préhistoire au Moyen Âge, Vol. 1. Les cahiers de la MSHE Ledoux 15, Presses universitaires de Franche-Comté. Besançon, 2022, 346 pp. ISBN: 978-2-84867-845-0 (edición impresa), 978-2-84867-946-4 (edición electrónica). DOI: https://doi.org/10.4000/books.pufc.46572</title>
      <link>https://carlosrellan.github.io/publication/journal-article/2024_archaedyn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carlosrellan.github.io/publication/journal-article/2024_archaedyn/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Iberian Peninsula during the green-axe Neolithic craze</title>
      <link>https://carlosrellan.github.io/publication/journal-article/2024_halle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carlosrellan.github.io/publication/journal-article/2024_halle/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://carlosrellan.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carlosrellan.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Aerial Prospection for Monitoring and Preserving Cultural Heritage in Northeastern Africa</title>
      <link>https://carlosrellan.github.io/publication/journal-article/aerial-prospection-heritage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carlosrellan.github.io/publication/journal-article/aerial-prospection-heritage/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desenredando el caos. Un análisis de la circulación de los adornos de piedra verde durante la Prehistoria Reciente de la Península Ibérica a través de la investigación de redes</title>
      <link>https://carlosrellan.github.io/publication/journal-article/2023_caos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carlosrellan.github.io/publication/journal-article/2023_caos/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>https://carlosrellan.github.io/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carlosrellan.github.io/experience/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANDALUSIL</title>
      <link>https://carlosrellan.github.io/project/andalusil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carlosrellan.github.io/project/andalusil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The ANDALUSIL project -&lt;strong&gt;Procurement strategies and production processes of sillimanite polished tools during the Late Prehistory of Andalusia&lt;/strong&gt;- is funded by the Ayudas para incentivar la Consolidación Investigadora 2022, Programa Estatal para Desarrollar, Atraer y Retener Talento. Plan Estatal de Investigación Científica, Técnica y de Innovación 2021-2023. Plan de Recuperación, Transformación y Resiliencia. Ministerio de Ciencia e Innovación (CNS2022-136083. 2023-2025).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sillimanite was extensively used as a raw material for manufacturing polished tools during Late Prehistory. Its widespread spatial and chronological presence, along with the social significance attributed to artifacts made from this material, highlight its importance. However, uncertainties persist regarding the geological origin, production, distribution, and consumption of sillimanite axes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ongoing research suggests two distinct procurement and production strategies for sillimanite polished artifacts in Andalusia, spanning the Neolithic and Early Bronze Age. The first strategy, characterized by specialization, involved direct mining of the highest quality material from primary outcrops. This material was then transformed in nearby small workshops, as observed in other European regions. In contrast, another strategy relied on utilizing natural blanks that had been remobilized. These blanks were minimally modified to create simple tools, representing a more opportunistic approach primarily focused on self-consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test this hypothesis and enhance our understanding of the supply and production strategies of sillimanite polished axes during the Late Prehistory of Andalusia, we introduce the ANDALUSIL project. This project aims to conduct a comprehensive study and analytical characterization of the supply sources, perform an archaeological survey of extraction and production contexts, and carry out a morphotechnical analysis of the products generated during the manufacturing process. These steps will serve as a preliminary stage for recreating the manufacturing process through experimental archaeology. Furthermore, in conjunction with other ongoing research efforts, the project will analyze the distribution and consumption patterns of sillimanite axes documented in Andalucía.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARPA</title>
      <link>https://carlosrellan.github.io/project/arpa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carlosrellan.github.io/project/arpa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The ARPA project -&lt;strong&gt;Computational Analysis of exchange networks in Andalusian Late Prehistory&lt;/strong&gt;- (EMERGIA20_00349. 2022-2025) is funded by the Emergia Program, Plan Andaluz de Investigación, Desarrollo e Innovación de la Junta de Andalucía. It aims at fostering a substantial transformation in our understanding of the characteristics, functioning and evolution of the exchange networks that were operative in Southern Iberia between the Late Neolithic and the Copper Age (c. 4200 - 2200 cal. BC), as well as in our knowledge of the socioeconomic processes that explain their emergence and subsequent transformations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To this end, we will analyze the distribution of a specific type of artifact –polished sillimanite axes- throughout the territory of the current Autonomous Community of Andalusia (Southern Spain). This study will be implemented through the application of powerful and innovative tools that take full advantage of the possibilities offered by a wide range of concepts and methodologies taken from disciplines as different as Computer Science, Network Analysis, Applied Statistics, Geographical Analysis, Geology and -of course- Archaeology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://proyectos.ugr.es/arpa/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt; or follow us on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ARPA_emergia&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/ARPAproject&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@proyectoarpa2835&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Youtube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iroutes APP MOVIL</title>
      <link>https://carlosrellan.github.io/apps/iroutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carlosrellan.github.io/apps/iroutes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Iroutes is a App for Android which has been designed to facilitate the visit to archaeological sites (prehistoric burial mounds and ancient livestock huts) in the Serra de Barbanza (A Coruña, Galicia). Users will be able to walk several trails along which information will be provided on the different archaeological sites that can be visited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This app is the result of the research carried out in the framework of the &amp;ldquo;Ocupación de las zonas altas del Noroeste peninsular a lo largo de la historia: la Sierra del Barbanza (A Coruña)&amp;rdquo; research project, funded by the Programa Estatal de Fomento de la Investigación Científica y Técnica de Excelencia, Subprograma Estatal de Generación de Conocimiento (HAR2015-67435-P).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arte rupestre galega</title>
      <link>https://carlosrellan.github.io/apps/arte_rupestre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://carlosrellan.github.io/apps/arte_rupestre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Arte rupestre galega is a simply Shiny and Leaflet web app exploring Galician prehistoric rock art. Users can explore the more than 3.000 rock art sites included in the Dirección Xeral de Patrimonio Cultural (Xunta de Galicia). Petroglyphs can be selected by type of engraving (cup marks, cup and rings, labyrinths, animals, weapons, crosses, prehistoric varia and historic varia) and municipality. A barplot explores the number and type of engravings within each municipality.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
